AS YOU STOOD BY
EUN-SU, HUI-SU AND US
Mr. Jin!
Hui-su has disappeared.
What do you mean?
What if Jang Kang got her?
Or Jin-young could have
done something to her!
Cool it. Just pull yourself together.
We're gonna find her, okay?
- You need to find Jang Kang.
- Yes, sir.
Some woman called
Hui-su's mother's nursing home,
claiming she was her niece.
It's Jin-young.
- Eun-su.
- Yeah?
We've got this.
MOM
I'M SORRY TO LEAVE YOU ALL ALONE
I COMMITTED AN UNFORGIVABLE SIN
I KILLED JIN-PYO
EUN-SU
People always take the elevator,
even if it's just one floor.
When people go to the garage,
they don't even think of using the stairs
'cause they have stuff to carry.
That's why the camera in the stairwell
wasn't repaired right away.
Nothing ever happens there.
It sucks we don't have any footage.
I mean, I get it. In apartment complexes,
new expenses need residential approval,
and there's lots of red tape and stuff.
People never take action
until someone gets hurt.
Hey, you see that?
I'm thinking
the bastard knows
how to avoid surveillance cameras.
Or the bitch.
What?
Why would she... try to mislead us?
Gyeong-gu?
What's up?
SEARCHING
BREEZE H...
POLICE ACADEMY
SEARCH ALUMNI
NOH JIN-YOUNG
12 PYEONGCHANG 7-GIL
GANGNAM POLICE STATION
What's the matter? It's late.
Yeah, I know, Jin-young. So sorry.
I wouldn't have called you,
but here's the thing.
You know the surveillance footage
for the murder case
at your brother's apartment complex?
Mm.
Some of it was corrupted,
but we were able to restore it.
You were?
Yeah, and I saw your brother.
He was in a part that was erased.
It was so weird.
My brother?
That's not possible.
Listen, did you see it?
Were you able to see the part
where your brother appeared?
You're making it sound like
I'm the one who deleted it.
He's family. It's only normal
to wanna protect your loved ones.
I didn't protect anyone.
I never saw my brother on the footage.
It couldn't have been him anyway.
Yeah, well, I was told
your brother was there that day, actually.
My sister-in-law said so, right?
Ah, well, I'm not at liberty to say.
Did you check my brother's travel records?
Did you look into it?
He wasn't even in the country.
I remember telling you that.
My sister-in-law's a loose cannon.
She once hurt herself
to make it seem like--
No, I verified her medical records.
It was clearly a case of domestic abuse.
What?
What's this about?
It's beside the point.
Look, I gotta get going.
Hey, did you speak to my sister-in-law?
I gotta go. Talk later.
Gimme a sec.
Shit.
MOM
Hi.
Sweetheart, I'm very confused.
The police are here. It's still dark out.
They keep ringing the doorbell,
asking for Jin-pyo.
Don't let them in!
Ask to see their badges! Get their names!
They have to tell you
what station they're from, okay?
Right. It's Detective Choi Gyeong-gu.
- From the Gangnam Police Station.
- Oh no!
Don't let him in!
- He says it'll only take five minutes.
- Oh God! Don't say a word!
Don't answer the door,
and don't pick up the phone.
And when the cops leave,
head over to my place.
Why should I do that?
Too many people
know where you live is all.
Just listen to me
and do what I'm saying, Mom!
I'll head over there now.
Wait, Jin-young.
Gyeong-gu.
Yeah, what's up?
Turns out, Mr. Noh was out of the country.
What?
He left the country
a month and a half ago.
JO HUI-SU
DETECTIVE CHOI HERE
FROM THE GANGNAM STATION
You must be swamped,
but you take time to come check in.
You really are one of a kind.
You know the saying,
"Connections aren't beside you,
but above you?"
Do you think you can provide me
with connections from now on?
I'll do my very best to help.
I'll make sure to give your best regards
to Chief Min.
Great!
Sir, uh, have you heard about the guard
that was killed
at the Breeze Apartment Complex?
It's actually in your jurisdiction.
I have.
Chief Min's on the case.
And?
This woman told me about her mother,
who lives alone in the complex.
She seems legitimately worried.
She said the young detective in charge
had been poking around a lot.
It's making the residents
feel uncomfortable.
Really?
Yes, she even asked if we could
take him off the investigation.
- Jin-young.
- Hey!
- Congratulations, Jin-young.
- Well done.
- Congrats, Jin-young!
- Great going!
♪ You're the best one for the job ♪
♪ You're the best one
You're the best one ♪
♪ You're the best one for the job ♪
No!
Hui-su's alive.
That was Jin-young.
Hui-su!
Hang on!
Hui-su! Wake up, Hui-su!
- It's all right.
- Hui-su!
- No, Hui-su--
- Let's get her to a hospital.
Oh my God!
This is bad.
Move, dammit!
Excuse me, ma'am! Hey, wait!
EMERGENCY ROOM
Ms. Jo Hui-su
was just transferred to Seoul.
Which hospital? Where was she taken?
I can't share that information with you.
I need it for an investigation.
Uh, one moment, please.
HUI-SU
The caller you are trying to reach
is not available.
Please leave a message.
Where are you?
Where is she?
You're evil.
I'm not the one who has committed murder.
You knew what he was doing to her.
If you'd tried to help her,
justice could've been served,
and he'd be alive.
You're a psychopath.
You killed him, and you wanna blame me?
All right! Go tell the cops!
You've got no proof of anything,
you idiot.
- You know what he did.
- What about what you bitches did?
Hui-su should've died last night.
Then maybe I'd have let you live.
Did you tell her
to kill herself in order to keep me alive?
Unbelievable.
I wasn't thinking.
You should've died together
in a suicide pact.
Listen closely, you monster.
If you mess with Hui-su again,
I'll destroy your precious little career.
So back the fuck off.
Yeah?
If I backed off, you bitch,
I'd have never come this far.
You won't win.
I'll make sure you pay.
CHAIRMAN JANG MIN-HO FROM WANGSIMNI
MRS. YANG JU-SEON FROM APGUJEONG-DONG
WIFE OF 5-TERM ASSEMBLYMAN
HWANG JUN-MO
I think she'll make a full recovery, sir.
JIN-YOUNG
5 MISSED CALLS
RECENTS
JIN-YOUNG
This is Detective Choi Gyeong-gu.
I fear you may not have been
completely honest with me yesterday.
Please contact me immediately.
JIN-YOUNG
ATTACHMENT: 1 VIDEO
Another person has to die
because of you.
Too bad.
Hui-su! Wake up!
Eun-su, can you get the door?
Hey!
Are you okay?
I am, yeah.
I know you can't eat yet,
so just look at it for now.
They say red is supposed to
make your mouth water, boost energy,
and give you courage.
You talked with Jin-young, right?
You know what?
I've gotta say these past few weeks
made me feel so alive.
I've been letting my guard down.
I feel safe.
I'm at peace.
That, to me, is a huge win.
I feel like over the past few months...
I've gotten a little closer
to stepping out of the darkness.
All right. Enough waiting. I'm starving.
Ms. Jo.
- Oh.
- You're off today, aren't you?
You're right, but I had the feeling
someone would come to see me.
Oh.
You're doing great.
Are you Jo Eun-su?
Yes.
I need you to come with us
for questioning.
- On suspicion of accepting a bribe.
- Let's go to the station, ma'am.
JO EUN-SU
RECORDING
STANDBY
Any thoughts
now that you're here?
Is Jang Kang better hidden this time?
I gave it some thought
and figured it was you.
Is he still alive and well?
There's no need for you
to worry about that.
We need to finish our talk from earlier.
I hear your father is about to retire.
I know he was
just a low-level civil servant,
but he still deserves to get
one of those plaques
with his name engraved on it.
Don't you think he should get one?
How long do you think
your mother will take to get here?
I want Hui-su.
Yes, ma'am?
Is it true that you assisted
your older brother in fleeing the country?
He's a white-collar criminal
and embezzler?
Excuse me?
And did you put pressure
on his securities firm to cover it up?
Of course not.
I'd never do that, ma'am.
I expect a formal response in my office
by the end of the day.
Ma'am?
Shit.
I didn't mention how violent he was,
and what followed.
Stop fucking with me!
Hey, easy!
- Ms. Jo's attorney's here!
- How dare you assault my client!
Fuck me.
Please, wait here a moment.
Mr. Jin sent me, ma'am.
MOM
I'm driving. I'll call you later!
Jin-young! It's that man.
- I can't hear you. I'll call you later!
- Jin-young!
It's that... that man.
Thank you, Mr. Jin.
Go get both your passports and suitcases.
Once I get the two of you on a flight,
I'll handle the rest.
- Not a chance!
- Cut it out.
Uh-huh?
Jang Kang could be there, so stay alert.
Please...
Shit.
Oh shit.
A FEW HOURS AGO
J... Jin-pyo?
Jin-pyo! Jin-pyo!
What are you doing on the floor?
Come on. Get up, Jin-pyo!
Wake up! Jin-pyo! Oh!
What's going on with you? Goodness!
Mom.
Could you untie me?
Who are you?
I'm Jin-pyo.
Your son.
Mom?
Mom, I'm in pain.
Please untie me.
Th... That watch.
It's Jin-pyo's.
Give it back!
Why the hell are you wearing it?
For fuck's sake.
Who cares about the watch?
- Shit!
- Ah!
Like mother, like daughter.
Wow, you two are really alike.
You probably don't care Jin-pyo's dead.
What?
He's...
What did you just say?
Your son is dead. Gone forever.
Oh.
It's been a while now.
You're lying!
You should ask your damn daughter
if I'm lying to you.
She knows.
But first, get me the fuck out now!
Tell me what you did to my son.
What did you do?
You really should've raised
your kids better.
You failed.
Your son's a loser. A worthless disgrace.
Fucking hell.
He's the reason my life's
all fucked up right now.
Your precious son's an asshole.
Jin-pyo was just a waste of flesh.
He deserved to die.
This is crazy.
That bastard murdered my baby boy,
didn't he? Didn't he?
- Jin-pyo was killed! What happened?
- Hey!
Do you want us both
to end up like Jin-pyo?
I... could lose everything because of this.
We'll be charged with murder!
You want that?
You need to get a grip, Mom!
Pull yourself together,
or we're both going down.
Keep pushing.
Wait, stop.
Okay, now come. This way.
Lift.
Yeah, what's up?
Jin-young loaded something
into her trunk and left.
I'm pretty sure it's Jang Kang.
I think he's dead, sir.
What?
She's with her mom.
They could be going somewhere
to dump the body.
All right.
On my way now. Just keep a close watch.
Hang on for a sec.
I should go.
That's not an option. Hui-su and--
Please, I have to do it.
No way.
I started this,
so I should be the one to finish it.
Eun-su, it'll be over soon.
It's almost over. I just need you
to take Hui-su and leave the country.
- Could you please do that?
- Mr. Jin.
Yes, what do you want?
Ma.
Are you sure Jang Kang's dead?
Okay, I gotta get going.
Please take care of Hui-su.
Eun-su?
I want you to have this just in case.
Okay.
You have gone off-road.
Eun-su's the one going.
I want you to keep your eyes on her.
You have gone off-road.
Hey, um, where did Eun-su go?
You have any idea where she went?
Hmm?
All right. I've got eyes on her car.
Oh shit.
All right. Time to let my crazy bitch out.
I admit I killed my husband.
Somebody should get help.
Call an ambulance or something!
That car crashed
into the other one.
Someone's getting out of that one.
Oh my God. What do we do?
Get the camera!
You've gotta get a shot.
Look, there's a body there!
Goddammit!
Oh shit! Shit! Get away from me!
I know that person!
- Call an ambulance!
- It's that famous lecturer!
Ms. Eun-su, are you okay?
Yeah.
No!
On the night of October 30th,
I killed Noh Jin-pyo.
He was my husband.
And yesterday,
his sister, Jin-Young, tried to kill me.
MA HAE-RYONG
Hey.
Around 7:00 p.m. tonight,
a shocking discovery was made
in a three-car collision
near the outskirts of Seoul.
The body of a man was found inside
the trunk of one of the impacted vehicles.
The police have taken three drivers
and one passenger
involved in the crash into custody.
The driver of the vehicle
carrying the body
has been identified
as an active-duty officer, Captain Noh.
Noh's mother, a well-respected lecturer...
Everything was caught
on the dashcam.
There's no way she can deny it.
Why would she do that?
Get to work.
Mind your business. Go on.
If you're feeling overwhelmed,
we can stop for today
and talk some more tomorrow.
No, we don't need to stop.
You and Hui-su are so alike.
I need to know if she's all right.
She is.
That's so good to hear.
I'll tell you everything.
I visited with Ms. Jo.
No need to worry.
She's gonna be all right.
Thanks so much, sir.
We will present
the best possible defense.
LAW FIRM BAEKSAN
Of course you will.
You're costing me a fortune.
Another murder
and attempted murder
came to light
during further investigation.
The police now suspect the incident
was not merely a traffic accident,
but may be connected
to a far more serious crime.
New video footage has surfaced
showing Noh, while on active duty,
attempting to murder
her sister-in-law, Jo Hui-su,
and staging her death as a suicide.
Noh remained silent
while being transported to police lockup.
Her alleged involvement
in such criminal activities
has brought significant disgrace
to the police force.
How are you gonna plead?
YOU ARE NO WOMEN'S ADVOCATE!
KO JEONG-SUK OUT
Hey!
Your twisted love for your child
is why he was murdered!
It's your fault!
You. I will sue you for defamation.
My son was the victim!
And I'm a victim too!
You can go straight to hell!
Now it's about to be
where you're going, lady!
The officer's mother,
also accused of the crime,
claimed that she was, in fact,
the real victim.
- The crowd reacted with outrage.
Now for the economy.
With the end of the year approaching,
consumer confidence has weakened,
putting the retail industry on...
Hello?
Hello, Mrs. Kim.
I'm calling from Lavie Department Store.
I want to sincerely apologize
for the trouble
one of our employees has caused you.
Everything has been worked out.
Oh, that's good to hear.
I just hope Ms. Jo
isn't seriously injured.
TO MASTER KIM DAE-CHEOL
COURTROOMS
Please make your final statement.
During my marriage,
my husband's behavior made me...
want to end my own life.
I'd speak to the heavens, to no avail.
The beatings were constant.
I was wasting away in unbearable pain.
I came to realize...
it was never going to stop...
...if I didn't take action.
In the end, I...
I decided to kill my husband.
I'm well aware
that I'm to blame for his death.
I understand that there is no excuse
for committing murder.
And so I believe...
I should be punished for my crime.
Defendant Jo Eun-su.
Your final statement, please.
When I was small,
I would hear my mother getting beaten.
I would take my little brother
by the hand,
and we would go hide in the closet.
Then once it grew quiet,
I'd come out, eat, and watch TV.
I would act like everything was fine
and nothing had even happened.
At the time,
I thought it was because I was afraid.
I understood much later
that I'd become indifferent.
I'd learned to look away.
Even as a child, I knew deep down
that domestic violence was a crime.
But
much later,
I realized I was... also to blame.
By pretending I saw nothing,
I was also committing a crime.
I came to that conclusion
many years later, as an adult.
I now understand that it is not only
the abuser who is guilty.
Because if you turn a blind eye,
you are complicit.
Not helping someone
who's being abused is criminal.
I know my actions have shocked many.
But I know
I did everything in my power
to save my friend.
Hey, Gye-sun.
I'm finally free now.
I left the house with Eun-hyeok.
It's not what you think. Don't worry.
I simply collected my things
and walked out of there.
That was all it took.
But for all those years,
I couldn't bring myself to do it.
I am so sorry
for putting you
in that foster home for a while,
when you were little.
I know you remember everything.
Your brother was just a baby, you know?
I figured you'd be safer there
while I got our affairs ready so I could
leave the house with Eun-hyeok.
But then, he fell really ill,
quite suddenly.
Running away
would have put his life at risk.
But the moment I heard you say
you wanted to come home,
I took you out of that place.
But I can only imagine...
...how scared you were
being left there for ten days.
I was just a kid, and I believed
I needed to stay close to my dad.
I wanted us to all be together.
I wasn't concerned about you.
I didn't know any better,
and my selfishness
caused you to stay with Dad.
You ended up spending your whole life
getting beatings from Dad,
not to break up the family.
I knew everything.
And I was afraid
I would end up just like you.
I was a coward.
I didn't have the courage
to face the truth.
I masked all my fear
with a stupid superiority complex,
thinking I was better than you.
I'm so sorry, Mom.
Oh, honey.
And I know...
...I wasn't grateful enough.
Mom...
...thanks for protecting us.
Mom, these are your favorite wildflowers.
I'm doing well now.
My heart's at peace.
Inmate 2083.
Hui-su! Hui-su!
Eun-su! Hi!
Mm.
Mr. Jin.
Ah, Mr. Jin. Thanks for everything.
It wasn't my idea,
but... she insisted I buy it.
Wanna have a bite?
Mmm!
- Delicious!
- Oh yeah?
All right. Enough of this.
You need real food.
- Let's do it.
- Yeah?
I can't wait.
You two have some pretty hard work
ahead of you.
This is nice.
Mom. Dad. You're finally together.
Take care of each other.
I'll come visit soon.
JINGANG CHINESE MARKET
Hui-su, can you check this?
- They only use quality ingredients.
- They do.
- You should order more next time.
- Okay.
- Bye, you two. Thanks.
- Okay. Take care.
Thank you.
Sorry.
Hi. How are you?
- Good, but what took you so long?
- Here.
Sorry.
People kept asking me
for this, but I had nothing to sell.
It's here now.
Right, but did you
fulfill the whole order?
Yeah.
So does this look right?
Yeah. This is perfect.
Hey, babe!
Get over here and check this inventory.
Hold your horses. I'm coming.
It's so hot outside.
You want something to drink?
It'll be my treat.
Here.
All right. Let's get ready
to make a wish, okay?
It's floating.
Oh!
Uh...
Did you make a wish?
Look! There it is. See?
It's floating away.
It's beautiful.
THERE IS ALWAYS LIGHT
AT THE END OF THE TUNNEL
I used to
pay very little attention to the weather.
But now,
it's the first thing I wonder about
when I wake up in the morning.
What kind of sky will greet me today?
- Good morning!
- Good morning.
See you later.
- Have a great day!
- Mm-hmm!
Even if good luck doesn't
wash over my life like crashing waves,
and even if rising tides
try to knock me down and swallow me whole...
I've learned not to back down
and to face each challenge with courage.
Because whatever wave
rolls my way tomorrow...
I just need to ride it.
♪ I used to not care ♪
♪ I never felt scared ♪
♪ I only pretend ♪
♪ I'm all right ♪
♪ Tell my white lies ♪
♪ Till the day comes ♪
♪ Let it all go ♪
♪ In the high tide ♪
♪ Even if I crash to the shore ♪
♪ I will always find a way to rise ♪
♪ 'Cause I breathe ♪
♪ Like I'm living
For the very first time ♪
♪ Yeah, I... ♪
♪ Yeah, I would ride ♪
♪ This wave again ♪
♪ 'Cause I know that I'll survive ♪
♪ The ocean pulls me in ♪
♪ But I won't ever drown ♪
♪ Keep my feet on solid ground ♪
♪ Yeah, I won't be afraid ♪
♪ Wash it away ♪
♪ I used to not care ♪
♪ Never felt scared ♪
♪ I only pretend ♪
♪ I'm all right ♪
♪ When the sky clears ♪
♪ Still, I'll be here ♪
♪ Never swaying ♪
♪ In the high tide ♪
♪ Even if I crash to the shore ♪
♪ I will always find a way to rise ♪
♪ 'Cause I breathe ♪
♪ Like I'm living
For the very first time ♪
♪ Yeah, I... ♪
♪ Yeah, I would ride ♪
♪ This wave again ♪
♪ 'Cause I know that I'll survive ♪
♪ The ocean pulls me in ♪
♪ But I won't ever drown ♪
♪ Keep my feet on solid ground ♪
♪ Yeah, I won't be afraid ♪
♪ Wash it away ♪
♪ I'm already floating ♪
♪ Over troubled water ♪
♪ No forsaking ♪
♪ Heartbeat steady ♪